supply and demand a simple Market
concept that can be used as the
foundation behind a highly profitable
trading strategy but like most trading
Concepts a lot of people get it wrong in
the next few minutes I'm going to show
you how you can Master supply and demand
trading so that you can start building
out a winning system so stick around and
I'll give you everything you're going to
need what is supply and demand it's a
concept that allows us to determine
areas of strong buying or selling using
zones this is a supply Zone and this is
a demand zone so supply and demand zones
show prices that large buyers or sellers
were happy to pay for an asset it's seen
as a consolidation or piece of sideways
price action before a big up or down
move and what it's showing is an area
where the buyers or sellers collected
orders before actually releasing those
orders to the market which is where the
big high momentum move kicks in here's a
simple supply and demand equation when
demand is up Supply is down and when
demand is down Supply is up high demand
leads to Rising prices and high Supply
leads to Falling prices why because the
market is an auction if a lot of people
are willing to bid at the current price
for an asset people will ask more for
the purchase if everyone wants what you
have however you can ask for more in
return When demand is low there are a
lot of units readily available to be
sold to the market but not enough buyers
willing to pay a premium price so the
market has to fall into place to meet
the buyer demands when we can
successfully mark up zones and
understand what they're telling us we
can get some really great entries for
app positions leading to high risk
reward and high accuracy tra so how do
we mark up supply and demand zones on
our charts marking supply and demand is
very important if you mark it
incorrectly you'll mess up your entire
strategy from the beginning but if you
do it right you'll be able to get sniper
entries like this this and this now
there's a commonly known way to Mark
supply and demand most people use the
last down candle before the up move like
this and the last up candle before the
down move like this now this works fine
and is a good general rule but
personally I do it a little bit
differently I Mark supply and demand
based on the last candle before the
impulse aka the last candle before the
big move up or down this makes more
sense to me from a logical perspective
because I'm actually looking at the
direct area where the massive buying or
selling came from also most of the time
it gives me more refined entries so I
can get in with smaller stop losses to
maximize my reward on each trade and one
more note the supply or demand Zone
always has to be imbalanced if it
doesn't have an imbalance leading into
it it's not a zone I'm interested in
trading at all it's important that you
always trade with the trend if you you
don't understand Trends watch this video
it's on Market structure that's going to
explain everything to you there's a card
somewhere in the top corner of this
video when you go to your charts you'll
realize there seemingly supply and
demand zones everywhere and much like
all other Market Concepts if you can't
Define which zones matter and which ones
don't you'll soon be left with a chart
clouded with random boxes that you can't
make sense of and this will do more harm
than good a very simple but very
important rule is to always trade Supply
or Demand with the trend Supply is
selling and demand is buying this simple
tip will eradicate half of the zones and
streamlines our Focus onto the zones
that matter and sometimes when you're
moving with the trend there are going to
be multiple zones to pick from but
fortunately for you I have another video
which goes in depth on this topic once
again there's a card somewhere on the
screen for you to go and watch that so
now let's take a look at the benefits of
supply and demand trading benefit number
one simplify your trading supply and
demand simplifies the way you trade if
you start to use supply and demand for
all your entries you'll be able to cut
out a lot of other confusing Concepts
and streamline your focus to only buying
or selling from these areas it's a very
easy way to execute trades and it makes
a lot of sense from a logical point of
view once you know how to accurately
Mark zones it becomes a very easy
concept to follow be warned though you
do still need other Concepts or you will
go insane I find market structure
imbalances and liquidity paired with
supply and demand to be an awesome combo
you can find lessons on all of these
topics on my YouTube channel benefit
number two get higher trade accuracy
while supply and demand zones will
sometimes fail as with every other
concept in a probability based Market
the entries that you do get on the
trades that work out will be highly
accurate markets react to supply and
demand more than almost anything else so
if you place orders in Supply or demand
zones you can really get some sniper
entries with smaller stop losses and
bigger take profits this added accuracy
makes up for the losses that you do take
by giving you a brilliant Roi on the
trades that work out and benefit number
three supply and demand Works in all
markets on all time frames supply and
demand as a concept is ingrained into
the way that the market works it
revolves around the auction that's
happening in every Market every day and
for this reason you can jump into
absolutely any Market Forex indices
stocks cryptocurrencies or Commodities
and you'll be able to apply the theory
and methods of supply and demand trading
successfully and it's also applicable to
every time frame you'll be able to see
supply and demand working its magic on
the one minute time frames the 1 hour
time frames and even the one day or one
week time frames too this is awesome for
two reasons number one whether you want
to day trade or swing trade you can
because it's going to work on every time
frame and number two if you ever want to
shift from day trading to swing trading
or vice versa you can supply and demand
makes you a flexible versatile and
adaptable Trader which is great for the
everchanging and ever harder to trade
markets of the modern day and if you
like today's video check out my free
course to learn more about the concept
of supply and demand along with nine
other lessons that will transform your
trading that's all from me I'll see you
in the next
[Music]
video